# Logan L. Cooper

Sandy Springs, GA

Phone: 678-882-5707 | Email: llc220@lehigh.edu LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/logan-cooper-6aa8a3134

#### Summary

Senior at Lehigh University pursuing B.S. in Computer Engineering. Minor in Economics. Wrestling on varsity high school team taught to be competitive, fearless, and dedicated. Learned the importance of communication and interpersonal skills. Gained interest in pursuing Computer Engineering degree after positive experiences building a PC and taking AP Computer Science in high school. Career interest in Software Engineering and Software Development.

## **Education**

Lehigh University Bethlehem, PA May 2020 (Greer Scholar)

Major: Computer Engineering Minor: Economics

**Related Coursework** 

**Software Engineering** 

- Full-cycle agile development in a small team on a web site/mobile app
- Worked as admin, front-end developer and back-end developer

**Operating System Design** 

- Gained deep understanding of key issues in Operating Systems from development in Unix-like systems
- Software implementation in C/C++ that interacts directly with Operating System

Computer Architecture

- Developed strong understanding on instruction set architecture (ISA) level and microarchitecture level
- Examined programming language level and logic gate level to deepen understanding of computing systems

# **Skills/Computer Languages**

Basic: • GIT • C/C++ • JavaScript • Android Studio • OrCAD • Cadence Virtuoso
Intermediate: • Java • Python • Assembly/MIPS Instruction set • HTML • Verilog
Advanced: • Excel • PowerPoint • MATLAB • Word • WordPress • Computer Repair

### **Related Experience**

Emory Healthcare Tucker, GA June 2019-August 2019;

IT Intern December 2019-January 2020

- Web developer for company intranet using Cascade content management system
- Provided data analytics for utilization, productivity, revenue, and other department operations frequently
- Performed department wide policy and procedure audits using company databases and documentation
- Implemented new solutions and assisted Education Coordinators with onboarding process for float pool staff

Lehigh University Bethlehem, PA August 2018-Present

Teaching Assistant

- Conduct collegiate lectures regarding course material
- Provide assistance to students with circuit design and programming in MATLAB/Arduino
- Oversee the completion of in-class assignments and final projects

National Society of Black Engineers Bethlehem, PA August 2016-Present

Member

Placed 2<sup>nd</sup> in hackathon at NSBE Region 2 FRC (2016) by designing and creating a working prototype for a mobile app

### **Work Experience**

Marshalls Dunwoody, GA June 2017-January 2019

Sales Associate/Inventory Management

- Managed and organized merchandise in assigned department
- Provided customer assistance
- Processed and placed merchandise on the sales floor from the backroom
- Loaded/unloaded shipments of merchandise received daily

# Leadership/Campus Involvement

- Served as Community Service Chair/GU rep for ACCC (African Caribbean Culture Club)
- Served as Secretary and Member of Events Planning Committee for BSU (Black Student Union)
- NSLS member (National Society of Leadership and Success)